RESIDENT PLAYBOOK
EPISODE 2
That can't be. Rounds are at 7:00 a.m.
Right. If the professor wants
to do them now, then we should.
Yes, I'll head down right away.
Hello?
An emergency?
Then we'll need Anesthesiology, Surgery,
Internal Medicine, Pediatrics…
And what else?
Right, I'll have our professor
and NICU prepared too.
Don't they know
how to throw away expired food?
Hello, Doctor.
I see.
The intern can't do it?
Can I just quickly eat first and…
Okay, I'm coming now.
Long time no see. Did you have dinner yet?
Of course not.
It's only Wednesday,
but why do I feel so tired already?
Because it's Thursday.
No, it's Friday.
You're kidding.
Still, we're getting off
early today. Right?
It's only 10:00 p.m. Isn't that a miracle?
Miracle…
my foot.
Fine.
I'll go first.
Hello. It's first-year resident Kim Sa-bi.
I'll begin the report.
Prof. Seo's third C-section patient today
had firm uterine contractions,
and her OP wound
looked good upon checking.
Prof. Kong's patient
is a primi at 32 weeks and zero days.
She's been receiving inpatient treatment
for preterm labor in MFICU
for five days now.
The ritodrine dose…
As for the ritodrine…
Thirty!
Right. She's still on 30 cc.
What? No, I knew that. I just said 30--
Don't tell me… Again?
Let's start over from the beginning.
She's had inpatient treatment
for preterm labor at MFICU
for five days now.
The ritodrine dose is at 30 cc.
This is Pyo Nam-kyung.
My report is for GYN.
Thank you and goodbye.
Sorry? Why would you need to hear it?
I see.
Just a moment.
In Room 1013,
a 74-year-old ovarian cancer patient.
POD is two since the debulking.
Sorry?
I haven't checked the cardiac markers yet…
I apologize.
Enough with the apologies, okay?
Start over from the beginning.
Hello, Chief.
Hey, Dr. Myeong.
I heard you did a debulking
for an ovarian cancer patient.
And the surgery took a while.
-I'm glad it went well though.
-Yeah.
-Here.
-What's that?
-Tea.
-You can put it here.
But how does an OB fellow
know about GYN surgeries too?
When you look after each of your juniors,
you end up learning everything.
I see. That's impressive.
Your OB schedule alone
would be hectic enough.
It's just my duty.
FIRST-YEAR KIM SA-BI
Chief.
When you go to that wine bar
with the professors next time,
couldn't you invite me too?
I've been wanting to check it out too.
-You like to drink, Dr. Myeong?
-I do.
There are five stages of grief
that humans go through.
You've all heard of them, right?
First, denial.
She just called me Dae-il earlier.
I told her numerous times
that my name was Um Jae-il.
Am I really that forgettable?
That can't be.
I'm the first-ever
K-pop idol-turned-resident, after all.
She probably just has trouble with names.
Right, Sa-bi?
The second stage is anger.
By the way, they're your own patients.
How do you not know them?
I'm not trying to blame you.
It's just that my plans
keep getting disrupted,
and it's frustrating for me too.
The third stage is
bargaining.
Delicious.
The fourth stage is…
Depression.
While someone's getting married
to a Kib & Chang lawyer
at Chilla Hotel next month…
Me?
I'm sure I'll be changing
dressings as always.
Hold on. What kind of purse is that?
It's so pretty.
And finally, the fifth stage.
It's Dr. Ki Eun-mi.
-Could it be?
-Is she telling us to go home?
She said we got
four more labor inductions tomorrow.
Then, that's seven in total.
We had five today.
Then, seven tomorrow.
Lucky seven.
The last stage is acceptance.
You eventually accept it.
We'll begin
the first-year resident report.
-That's from On Death and Dying, right?
-Yeah.
But those stages perfectly apply
to something else as well.
What's that?
The residents' escape and escaping.
Come on, already?
It's only been three weeks.
That's exactly the problem.
Three weeks is a very tricky period.
It's not long enough
to feel like a waste if you quit,
and you haven't bonded
with your peers enough to stay.
But most importantly, they haven't yet--
They haven't tasted
their first paycheck yet.
As sharp as ever, Do-won.
The warning signs have been showing
for a while, so hold onto them tight.
We've put in a lot of effort
to bring them in.
-Yes, ma'am.
You know, Professor.
It seems like you know everything.
There's one thing I don't know.
It continues to boggle my mind.
Why don't they want to do it?
Do what?
Obstetrics.
Why don't they want to do
something so wonderful?
I'll get going first.
Good night, Professor.
RESIDENT PLAYBOOK
Is that your dad's jacket?
What's that? A coin purse?
Hey, if you don't know, just keep quiet.
I had to get on a waitlist for this.
Is that so?
Hi!
Where are you going?
To study!
This is a case of dystocia,
type one.
There's not enough power.
To fully understand dystocia,
we need to establish the same criteria
for whether it's active labor or not.
For that to happen,
we need consistent measurements
regardless of who checks.
Now, let's go back to the basics.
Can someone give me
a simple definition of dystocia?
Difficult and abnormal labor process.
Yes. Spot on.
During childbirth and labor,
there are three factors
that can affect abnormal contractions.
Oxytocin.
It's when oxytocin is used, but…
But?
Oxytocin is used, but…
Despite using it…
Oh Yi-young, you came this unprepared?
I'm sorry.
Pyo Nam-kyung, give me your answer.
Despite the use of oxytocin,
it's when the baby doesn't descend
for more than two hours.
And…
Contraction.
Comp…
Compre…
Sa-bi said "contraction," okay?
Jae-il.
-Yes?
-Did you hear that?
Yes, I did.
Are Sa-bi and I
the only ones learning here?
This is like private tutoring then,
not a study group.
"Private tutoring"?
Professor, it's almost time for rounds.
I'll be there.
Let's have Da-hye and Nam-kyung
prepare the next session.
-Okay.
Yes, ma'am.
Do-won went to a conference
with Prof. Im Dong-ju, right?
-Is he returning tomorrow?
-No, the day after.
I see.
You're not going to make rounds, Yi-young?
Right!
Dr. Oh.
If we have seven C-sections in a day,
that means we'll have
seven post-op day two patients, right?
Yes, that's right.
Then, when you present them,
mention their characteristics
so I can better remember who's who.
Right. I'm sorry.
And for Ms. Yoon Seon-mi, it's normal
to not have reactivity at 22 weeks.
-So no need for an NST.
-Yes, ma'am.
And check on transferring
Ms. Sim Hui-yeong.
Yes, ma'am.
Hello, this is Jongno Yulje.
We have a 34-week primigravida
whose baby is small,
so we've been monitoring her.
Her amniotic fluid has decreased
and things don't look good.
I think we need to deliver the baby,
but we don't have any NICU beds.
What? One moment, please.
The baby is 1.5 kg,
and the AFI is…
Four.
Sorry? The paperwork?
Yes, I'll have it ready.
Okay, thank you. Goodbye.
-Dr. Oh.
-Yes?
Why do you do your job like such a fool?
Sorry?
I mean, you stutter
and speak so strangely.
Strangely?
Yi-young, have you arranged
Ms. Sim's transfer?
Yes, I'm working on it.
Include her early prenatal test results
when you prepare the request.
That'll save you time.
Okay. Thank you.
Exactly.
That's exactly what I meant.
Dr. Oh, when you're working,
don't just make calls right away.
First,
use your head.
Is your heart not in it?
You don't have an ounce of passion in you.
What is she talking about?
-Hello!
-Hello.
Hello, let me help you.
Thank you.
Okay. This way, please.
Obstetrics is this way.
I'm not pregnant.
I'm fine.
Ms. Yeom Mi-so.
Hello.
You should've just stayed in the ER.
I heard you're feeling weak.
Here you go.
-Careful.
-Gosh.
The professor wants to drain
the fluid in your abdomen first.
Chemotherapy will be scheduled after that.
All right.
You don't look very well today.
How can I when I'm at a hospital?
But…
I'm especially irritable today.
Let's go.
Sure.
I don't think
you're cut out to be a doctor.
When I said I felt feverish,
you just said I was fine
and left without even looking at me.
Each time I checked your temperature,
it was always at 37.5°C with no fever.
Progesterone levels rise during pregnancy,
so it can feel like you have a fever.
Also, I think
you might be someone
who's naturally prone to feeling hot.
What? What did you say?
This is unbelievable.
Are you serious right now?
I'm not prone to feeling hot.
And I'm not dumb enough to confuse
feeling hot with having a fever.
And what about the dressings?
I've been here the past four weeks,
and this was the first time
the dressings hurt.
You came in without a word
and just jabbed me with a needle.
You know what she said
when I said it hurt?
"Feeling pain
can't be helped."
See? Doctor, did you hear that?
That's exactly what she said.
I see.
I was in pain,
and she said it can't be helped.
How could a doctor
say that to her patient?
Mom, do you still think
I'm being too sensitive?
How can I let someone
so apathetic deliver my baby?
Professor, this has never happened before.
You know that, right?
I apologize.
You must've been very frustrated.
I'll make sure this doesn't happen again.
Professor.
Someone like her
shouldn't be a doctor.
Right.
I can't believe this happened. Goodness.
Get some rest.
I'm not asking for a lot.
I didn't tell you
to do surgery or deliver a baby.
I said just do what you're told
without causing trouble.
Was that so difficult?
Go apologize. Tell her you were wrong.
In terms of medical facts,
I don't think I made
any errors or did anything wrong.
Then what did the patient do wrong?
What did she do so wrong
that she can't eat or sleep?
I'm not asking you to apologize
for making a mistake.
It's an apology to console.
An apology filled
with thoughtfulness and empathy.
You know, something like that.
Then, instead of apologizing,
I'll explain the situation to her
in more detail once again--
Just go and apologize to her!
Why are you so dense?
She wants to go to another hospital!
If a patient transfers like that,
who do you think people will blame?
You or me?
I'll have a talk with her.
I'll resolve this.
Good. Whatever it is, do it.
Do whatever it takes to fix this.
Yes, ma'am.
Dr. Kim. Your MBTI type
doesn't have an F, does it?
Sorry?
I don't think you're an F.
I got straight As.
You're a T.
Definitely a T.
Have you eaten?
How are you feeling?
Your numbers have improved a lot.
I see.
And you've started exercising, right?
No, not yet.
As I mentioned yesterday,
you need to exercise often
for your condition to improve.
Try to walk frequently.
But I'm so hungry
that I can't move around.
Have you not eaten
breakfast today…
You should've gotten your breakfast.
We didn't give you your food yet, did we?
I'm so sorry.
I'll arrange for your meal right away.
I'm sorry we made you fast
a bit longer than you needed to.
This shouldn't have happened.
I'm truly sorry.
Give her some water first.
-Yes, sir.
-Have some water first.
YEOM
ATTENDING DOCTOR: UM JAE-IL
ATTENDING DOCTOR: PYO NAM-KYUNG
I'm sorry you have to
suffer because of me.
I would've been upset too.
Why did you have to be a busybody
and get on a patient's bad side?
You're an enemy, not a colleague.
My horoscope said I'd encounter
an unexpected adversary today.
That was you.
I'm sorry.
But, Nam-kyung,
I think I could work in the ward
without Dr. Cha knowing.
-I can't sit here and do nothing.
-Don't.
If you get caught, I'll be dead too.
Just stay at the operating room.
You're only arranging surgeries.
Surely you can't mess that up.
Nam-kyung, have you eaten yet?
-You haven't eaten either, right?
-No.
I left lunch boxes in the on-call room.
You want them now?
-Okay--
-Later.
Eat first. You must be hungry.
Okay.
Make sure you eat.
I was about to get coffee.
Want some? What do you want?
-Iced Americano--
-Maybe later.
I don't have time right now.
Okay.
Eun-mi the Saint, as always.
Nam-kyung, you're lucky--
Of course I want to eat too. I do.
But I don't have the time.
I have to prepare for tomorrow's rounds
and do the dressings too.
Prof. Ryu has nine surgeries tomorrow,
and they're sending
another patient from the ICU.
Dressings alone take all day,
but they're adding another patient.
And that patient
you caused trouble with, Yeom Mi-so…
-She's apparently a nightmare.
-How so?
She complained about a four-person room,
so they moved her to a private one.
Then she wanted the room next door
with a bigger window.
-And she wants dressings changed--
-Excuse me.
You've only changed
my dressing twice today.
I see. Ms. Yeom Mi-so, right?
Yes.
I just received the transfer now.
I want them changed
four times a day, okay?
I see. Sure.
And please pay
special attention to being sanitary.
Okay?
Sure.
Want me to bring you your lunch box?
I said I don't have time.
Right.
Are you listening to music?
Then what are you listening to?
What are you listening to?
Okay. I'm sorry.
Goodbye.
-What were you listening to?
-Insults.
I guess she really hates me.
Dr. Myeong Eun-won?
The nurses told me
she's notorious
for being hard on first-years.
How childish. She should join the army
if she's that into disciplining people.
And apparently,
she's even more sensitive this year.
Why?
Prof. Im Dong-ju is retiring next year.
She transferred here
in hopes of taking that open spot.
The junior residents hate her,
but she seems to have
a good reputation among the professors.
They say her chances
of becoming a professor are high.
Our second year will be hard too
if she really does become a professor.
Good luck.
Hey, we're in the same boat.
Play some music.
There's a nice group called HI-BOYZ.
No, thanks.
Why not?
Run with me
It feels like we need to go somewhere
You look like you're about to cry
MYEONG EUN-WON
Hello, Dr. Myeong.
What?
Doctor, I'm really sorry.
Our patient has a history of myomectomy.
She went into active labor
with contractions every two minutes.
We need to do an emergency C-section.
What? Right now?
There aren't any ORs available.
Not a single one.
But we need one.
Please open a room for us.
If there's a room
that's just been used, I'll go clean it.
Please, just this once.
They'll be rushing down here
any minute now.
Your department is like the Grim Reaper.
I get chills whenever you guys call.
I'm sorry.
Her contractions
suddenly came every two minutes.
I have a child too.
I get where you're coming from,
but I wasn't lying
about not having any rooms available.
We were lucky this surgery ended early.
Thank you.
Dr. Myeong, I'll go
and escort the patient here.
No, I'll do it.
Stay there and hold onto the room. Okay?
Yes, ma'am.
CURRENT TIME
What's taking so long?
We put the next surgery on hold
because you said it was urgent.
I'll call her again.
It's not easy to time the delivery
if the surgery is decided suddenly.
Not only picking a surgery time
but also picking one at night
is almost impossible in Obstetrics.
If your daughter becomes president,
I get some credit too, right?
Goodness. Of course.
-The patient's contractions--
-Good work.
Professors don't usually
accommodate timing like this.
You're right.
I won't forget this kindness.
If you send your friends my way,
I'll take good care of them.
Okay. Thank you.
Dr. Joo, I appreciate your help today.
Dr. Myeong.
I heard this surgery was extremely urgent.
What? I'm not sure what you mean.
Did something happen?
You called me earlier and--
I did?
Right, we did talk on the phone.
What about it?
Sir, please give her
an epidural for the PCA.
Anesthesia with an epidural catheter
will take 30 minutes to work.
Look, Dr. First-Year. This isn't right.
You can't lie to other departments
to get what you want.
-That's not the case--
-Forget it.
What am I going to tell my professor?
This is so annoying. Damn it.
It's her first meal in days.
I shouldn't disturb her.
She said to be considerate.
Right.
Be considerate.
It's already 10:00 p.m.
Not sleeping is harmful for the baby.
This is empathy.
Empathy for the pregnant mother.
Yeah.
I wanted to shower today.
Forget it.
I can't do this anymore. Damn it.
YEOM
ATTENDING DOCTOR: PYO NAM-KYUNG
Ms. Yeom, are you feeling any better?
I'll change your dressing.
Did you wash your hands?
Yes, I did.
Wait.
Yes?
Can you wear new gloves?
I just put these on.
I'd like you to use new forceps too.
Sure.
I need this twice in the morning
and afternoon each. Four times total.
You know that, right?
I've been informed.
Please stick to that schedule.
I'm asking you for this favor.
Okay.
I'll remove the tape.
This might sting.
Um Jae-il…
Doctor, Ms. Park Ga-yeong has disappeared.
-She's scheduled for surgery today.
-Right, her.
She had severe pain from a ruptured cyst,
so we operated immediately.
Did I not tell you?
She's in the ICU right now.
Then, I'll go there--
That's not necessary. You should rest.
I'll call you if anything comes up.
Ms. Park liked me.
She asked me to be there for her surgery.
Excuse me. Doctor.
It's about Ms. Kim.
What do we do?
-Surgery's tomorrow.
-Ms. Shin is in a lot of pain.
No, I'll ask the professor…
Excuse me.
Ms. Park would like some consultation
on myomectomy tomorrow.
I think you should see her.
Ms. Oh's vitals are unsteady.
I think you need to take a look.
Where's Dr. Kim Sa-bi?
Where is she?
You have a conference.
Don't be late for it.
I clearly told you yesterday, didn't I?
I told you to go talk to her.
I did go, but she was eating.
I went again at night,
but she needs to sleep well.
So out of empathy and consideration--
Hey!
The patient was right.
Dr. Kim, how will you manage as a doctor?
You can't empathize
or get the timing right.
And you can't even pick up signs
your patient's sending.
That's why such a simple issue
has blown up like this!
No more excuses.
Just fix it somehow.
Fix it no matter what, got that?
Do it right now. Understood?
I won't stand this any longer.
This is
your last warning, okay?
What am I going to do?
All right, is it general anesthesia today?
Yes, it is.
Sang-hyeon, double-check everything.
Has the patient been fasting?
Yes, she's been fasting.
Sang-hyeon, did you check?
Did you ask the patient directly?
Yes, I did.
And operability?
PREOPERATIVE TESTS
I'll check.
Eun-won, has the operability
all been checked?
I thought this surgery had no indications,
so Pediatrics wasn't needed?
Dr. Myeong said you were needed.
I see.
Is the baby really in distress though?
Can I take your word for it?
Sorry?
You always say they are,
but they're fine when they come out.
I was suspicious of a few past cases.
I'm not sure
which cases you're referring to.
There were several.
Rather than say which specific ones…
I wonder if you're only calling us
so we take the blame
if something goes wrong.
What did you say?
You know Pediatrics
is severely understaffed.
I'm just saying
let's not lie to each other from now on.
That's what I'm saying.
-Hi.
-Hello.
Oh, no. You're missing lunch
because of us again.
I'm sorry.
Hey, first-year. Don't mess up today.
Everyone's working so hard.
Dr. Pyo.
Ms. Yu Jeong-hye in Room 1013
is post-op day two with a slight fever.
Has this antipyretic prescription
been confirmed?
Yes.
As for Ms. Kim Seon-a in Room 1016,
the professor said
her WBC count was too high
and asked for ESR and CRP tests.
After I do my charting first.
I have 20 charts backed up.
Okay.
Hello, Dr. Ki.
Hey, Nam-kyung.
We're at the cafeteria now--
I'm okay.
I have a backlog of work.
Could I take a rain check?
Okay, bye.
And…
It's time to change Ms. Yeom's dressing.
I think she'll make
a scene again if we're late.
She's so fussy for no reason!
Why does she want me to change
her dressing if my hands are that filthy?
It's not like a good dressing
will make her illness go away,
so why is she so obsessed with it?
Gosh, I hate her so much.
Mi-so? More like Mi-sad.
She always looks miserable…
Nurse Ju-yeon.
Yes?
Could you call the intern, please?
The intern?
I don't think I can change
Ms. Yeom's dressings anymore.
Geez, that's too harsh.
Right?
She shouldn't treat
a first-year like that.
I agree.
That's the fifth ambulance today.
Gosh, I bet the ER
is going to be short-staffed.
Yes, I'm coming right now.
Yeah, Dr. Um.
Pediatrics is severely understaffed.
-Be there in 30 seconds.
-Goodbye.
Hello, Dr. Cha.
I requested the urgent CT readings
you asked for
and called surgery to tell them
OR 11 has been car-inned.
Should I go straight to the OR?
That's okay.
I can finish up with the intern.
I see.
Then, you don't need me?
-No, it's okay.
-Dr. Cha!
Coming!
You can go home for today. Good work.
This is the first time in my life
I've ever been scolded.
Is this what you call
being "in the doghouse"?
I've fallen out of favor,
haven't I?
I think so.
I really like Professor Seo.
That's why I chose OB.
She must be so disappointed in me now.
What should I do?
Well, I don't know.
People get disappointed in me
all the time,
so it wouldn't really bother me.
But I don't know about you.
The patient said…
someone like me shouldn't be a doctor.
She speaks too harshly.
Like me.
Yi-young.
Do you really think someone like me
shouldn't be a doctor?
I'm not qualified, am I?
Are you quitting?
You're quitting as a doctor?
When?
I'm going to bear it
one more time and then quit.
No, I'll keep going.
I want to be a doctor.
Then do it.
If you want to, then do it.
Should I?
I'll keep going then, okay?
Yeah, sure.
I'll see the patient
one more time before I go. Bye.
She's a bit of a lunatic too.
MYEONG EUN-WON
I'm heading into surgery now.
Can you get consent forms
from tomorrow's surgical patients?
Again?
What? What did you say?
Hello?
Yes, ma'am.
Also, you didn't send one this morning.
Sorry?
Your photo.
What? Are you giving up already?
After just a few days?
I just sent it. I forgot.
Is that really the truth?
Lying is a habit too.
You need to develop
good habits from the start.
And you can't do whatever you want here.
This isn't your home.
That's not how things are done
at the workplace.
I'm saying all of this
for your own good, so…
Look at you.
You have a temper, don't you?
What?
"I'll do the suturing later"?
You've lost your mind. How dare you?
I may be broke, but I still have my pride.
I quit. I didn't want to do it anyway.
OB-GYN, code blue.
Main building, basement level 1.
-Is it a chemo patient?
-Main building, basement level…
Could it be…
A pregnant woman needs CPR?
But everyone on call is in surgery.
OB-GYN, code blue.
-Main building, basement level 1.
-No one's here.
-Damn it.
-Main building, basement level 1…
Damn it.
God, why isn't she picking up?
Excuse me. OB-GYN coming through.
Is she okay?
Let's switch. One, two, three.
Prof. Kong is almost done
with her surgery,
so I booked the OR next to it.
She'll come over right after
to do the C-section.
-We'll move the patient.
-Let's switch.
One, two, three.
-Raise her head a bit.
-Careful.
One, two, three.
-Continue CPR, please.
-Okay.
Excuse me.
What happened?
Good job. Go now.
Me?
There's no one to assist
in that room! Hurry!
Yes, ma'am.
Hello, Professor Seo.
Aren't you on call today?
Yes, I am.
Then, why didn't you pick up?
I was in surgery.
I see. Okay.
But which OR?
I was in surgery too.
Well…
I…
The surgery I was preparing for
was canceled, so I was resting.
I'm sorry.
What are you sorry for?
For lying?
Or for dawdling when they called
an OB-GYN code blue?
I…
Don't bother answering.
We'll no longer
be seeing each other anyway.
You sure are impressive, Dr. Oh.
A first-year who didn't panic.
I can't believe how calm you were.
The mother and her baby
are alive thanks to you.
Well done. I mean it.
Thank you.
Monitor her vitals carefully
today and tomorrow.
Yes, ma'am.
Tomorrow?
Excuse me.
Tomorrow, ma'am?
You want me to do it?
Then who will do it?
I'll do it.
You're much better than Dr. Kim Sa-bi.
Come to OB.
-If you join us, I'll--
-That's okay.
What I mean is…
I said that because I'm really okay.
Have a good night.
Geez.
They're all the same.
JONGNO YULJE MEDICAL CENTER
What? You're already here?
Or did you never leave?
No, I couldn't leave.
But today,
I'm definitely leaving.
What's with that backpack?
People might think you're running away.
Look. I--
Later. I haven't prepared
for rounds at all.
I didn't check the X-rays.
I'm so in trouble.
And the dressings.
When am I going to finish all of those?
Hey…
I went to talk to her,
but she wouldn't let me in.
She doesn't want to talk.
I really can't do this anymore.
Jae-il, we're not in the mood--
-Hello.
-Hi.
Hello.
-Did you have breakfast?
-No, I'm hungry.
But I have to go.
I bought some burgers. Won't you…
-What's going on--
-Thank you.
SPRING GIVEAWAY EVENT
Fine.
I'd just be a nuisance.
I'm neither helpful nor needed.
They're better off without me.
DR. CHA DA-HYE
I didn't run away.
I'm just late. I'm on my way.
What? Dr. Um?
Can you hear me?
Yes, Doctor. Loud and clear.
I didn't run away. I--
Today's surgery is five hours long,
so there's nothing to prepare during then.
There's nothing to do,
so get some sleep in the meantime.
She doesn't know
that I ran away.
Pyo Nam-kyung.
Yes?
How can you seriously have
an appetite right now?
Why do patients keep complaining
about the dressings?
-Well…
-What is it?
I'm sorry.
I thought you were at least good at that.
What's going on?
You don't even have that many patients.
Dr. Pyo.
Ms. Yeom from the private room
is asking for you.
-She says it's past time for her dressing.
-Me?
Can't someone else go instead?
She got very upset
when the intern came by yesterday.
She specifically wants you to do it.
What should we do?
Don't press too hard.
Please make it as painless as possible.
Okay.
Yesterday, I made a mistake…
I'm sorry.
From now on, another doctor will--
No.
I want you to do it.
-Sorry?
-Four times a day. Just like now.
If that's not possible,
I'll speak to the professor.
No, that's okay.
I will do it.
Professor Kong
yells at me
and tells me to get out.
Professor Seo
won't even look at me.
I…
don't think I can be a doctor.
MYEONG EUN-WON
You can't hang up.
I'm fine. You can go.
No, it's okay.
I've done everything she asked anyway.
Besides…
I'm leaving anyway.
You are?
To the ward? The OR?
Somewhere else.
-Hello.
-Hi.
-You're both here.
I was about to call you.
Sa-bi, Eun-mi's waiting in the cafeteria.
Right.
-Goodbye.
-Enjoy your meal.
And Dr. Oh--
Me? Why me?
I've done everything I was asked to do.
Yeah, that's why I have a favor to ask.
Can I see you in front of the ER
in ten minutes?
I let them know at Songdo.
-Am I going alone?
-Yeah.
If the baby suddenly comes out
on the way there,
clamp the umbilical cord with clips
and cut it with sterile scissors.
You're the attending doctor and surgeon
until she gets there. Got it?
You didn't bite.
You're quick to catch on.
You wouldn't send a first-year
if it was that dangerous.
Exactly.
I've checked the patient's condition,
so don't be too nervous.
You'll be fine on the trip.
And get some air too while you're away.
See you later.
Hello? I'm coming now.
It's the perfect weather for running away.
-Hello.
Doctor, how long will it take?
I think about an hour.
I see.
If you feel uncomfortable,
let me know right away.
Okay, Doctor.
Hello, Doctor.
Right, you're eating.
I'm sorry, but could you come here
in about ten minutes?
Sure. I'll go now.
Is that you?
Nam-kyung, is that you?
-What?
-It is!
I didn't know you worked here.
Right. It was Jongno Yulje.
You were in the middle of eating. Eat up.
No, it's fine. I'm done.
Hye-seon, what brings you here?
Why are you at the hospital?
The health checkup center director
is my future father-in-law's friend.
I'm here for a pre-wedding checkup.
Right, you're getting married.
You have to come, okay?
-Sure. I'll be there.
-Good.
Hey, I almost didn't recognize you though.
You look like a different person.
I've been a bit busy.
Hold on.
Hey, it's almost time.
I need to go first. Finish your meal.
What? Okay, bye.
Hello?
Dr. Pyo, it's Ms. Yeom.
She's complaining
that there's more discharge,
asking why
she hasn't received painkillers,
and she says her heart is beating faster.
-You should come and check--
-I can't go.
Sorry?
She seems bent on making me miserable
for speaking rudely to her,
but I'm not going anymore.
Someone else can do it,
or she can do it herself.
Just tell her to handle it herself.
I can't.
I can't do this anymore.
I've endured it for quite a while
I endured it for a long time
While I aged…
Hello.
Hello. Where would you like to go?
Myeongjin Studio Apartments…
No, the bathhouse.
No, wait.
The department store.
Take me to the nearest one.
Sure, okay.
-Sir, could you turn that up?
-Sure.
I'm leaving work
Now, to find my happiness
I'm going far, far away
I'm quitting
I'm going to quit
NURSE JU-YEON
Oh, whatever
I'm going to bet on myself
I'm leaving work
Sir, please turn around! Hurry!
I feel like my stomach
is tightening a bit.
That can't be.
Maybe I'm wrong.
But it feels different from when we left.
I should be okay, right?
Where exactly are you feeling discomfort?
The left side feels tight.
Just a moment.
-Hello?
-Dr. Ku.
We still have about 30 minutes to go,
but the patient says
her stomach suddenly feels tight.
How much pain is she in? Does it feel
like she needs to use the bathroom?
Does it feel like you need to push?
No, I don't think so.
She's neither in severe pain
nor does she feel like using the bathroom.
Do you see any amniotic fluid?
No, I don't.
It's not an urgent situation,
so monitor the baby's heart rate
with the Doppler
and check manually
if the contractions are okay.
Reassure the patient too.
Okay, I will.
Sir, please hurry.
-The number you called is unavailable…
-Who is she talking to?
After your call goes through…
I'm leaving a text
since you're not answering.
Please clean up the lines in Room 1011.
Room 1011 is Ms. Yeom's room.
Why suddenly clean up her lines?
PATIENT NAME
DEPARTMENT
Where did you go?
Dr. Ku cleaned up the lines for you.
Why all of a sudden…
Nurse.
Let me do the dressing just once.
Sorry?
I couldn't do it yesterday,
and I only did it once today.
So let me do it one last time.
Go ahead then.
But did you wash your hands?
Then I'll wash my hands first and…
What are you doing here?
To get my glasses.
How can you be an hour late?
There's discharge,
and my heartbeat seems irregular.
Where were you? I was so worried!
I moved to the room next door,
because the window there was bigger.
Good for you.
"Conta" will infect the area.
Something got in my eye.
How do you know that term?
Get treated as much as I do,
and you pick up things.
Don't worry.
I washed my hands twice,
and these gloves are brand-new.
Did you get in trouble because of me?
Or are you having a hard time
because of me?
No.
It's because of me.
I'm sorry if I've been a bother.
I'm sorry for being difficult.
That's okay.
The professor said
you were good at dressings.
I know applying this medicine
isn't a big deal,
but I thought it might be better
if someone who was skilled did it.
Three years of going through this
changes a person.
I know it's tough for you,
but…
I end up only thinking about myself.
I'm sorry.
No, dressings are important.
It's nothing trivial.
Good dressings help wounds heal faster,
and you can be discharged sooner.
And I'm really good at it.
I'm the best among the first-years.
Does that mean you'll come again tomorrow?
Yes. Four times.
Tomorrow morning.
Just come once in the morning
to remove my nasal tube.
Are you being discharged?
See? Your discharge came sooner!
You must be happy that I'm leaving.
No, I'm not.
No. Wait.
You're getting discharged.
That's the best news ever!
I'm also really good
at removing nasal tubes.
SONGDO YULJE MEDICAL CENTER
Are you okay?
Dr. Oh Yi-young?
Yes, that's me!
Hello.
You're from Jongno Yulje, right?
Why haven't you left yet?
I wanted to know if the patient was okay.
She kept saying
her stomach felt tight during the trip.
Then she said she was fine.
Then she said to hurry because it hurt.
But our doctor said she was okay.
Dr. Ku Do-won?
Yes.
But I'm just a first-year,
and this is all new to me.
I don't know her that well,
so I was worried.
I think she was in pain
because the uterine contraction inhibitor
didn't work properly.
I see.
She's fine now.
She's really okay.
You must've been very scared.
I was.
If a fourth-year says it's okay,
then it's really okay.
And if it's not okay,
then it's that doctor's fault.
That's the one good thing
about being a first-year.
If things go south,
you can blame your seniors
or whoever gave the orders.
You're right. It's all Ku's fault.
But even if it wasn't my fault,
if something had happened to the patient,
I would've never forgiven myself.
I should get going then.
Okay.
Hold on, Doctor.
Care to have some coffee before you go?
Sorry?
SONGDO YULJE MEDICAL CENTER
You must be an excellent first-year,
seeing how they sent you for the transfer.
Thank you.
Your seniors must adore you.
Not at all.
Come on.
Then those seniors are the problem.
You see, I barely made it into residency.
All I remember was being scolded
during the first three months.
Everyone would yell at me on sight.
It was my first time,
so how could I possibly know anything?
I couldn't understand them.
I felt so wronged.
But today, I finally realized
why I got scolded so much.
I was just a robot.
I just followed their orders,
whatever they were.
I wasn't concerned or sincerely interested
in the patients at all.
That's not something you can learn
or be taught, you know?
So of course I didn't know.
But you, as a first-year,
already knew that.
You should go before the traffic gets bad.
Here you go.
What's this?
It's for Dr. Ku.
Make sure he gets it today.
I see.
SONGDO YULJE MEDICAL CENTER
Okay.
It's important for the patient,
so please hurry. Okay?
Okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Hi, honey.
Yeah.
Kalguksu?
Sounds great.
Then, order some fresh kimchi for me.
Okay.
All right.
I love you more.
Okay.
Okay, all right. Bye.
We're newlyweds, you see.
I see.
Okay, Dr. Oh. Take care.
Thank you.
No need to thank me.
You were terrific today.
Let's definitely meet again, okay?
Damn it.
Hello.
I need to talk to you.
Okay.
I've been watching you.
Sorry?
Ms. Cheon Eun-pyo in MFICU.
Right. I'm sorry.
There's nothing to be sorry about.
If you really can't do it, then don't.
How about you try something else instead?
What?
I'll work hard!
Excuse me.
Dr. Kim.
Your snoring is keeping me up.
I'm sorry.
Are you protesting or something?
I'll accept this as your apology.
You can go.
Wait. The thing is…
I wasn't here to apologize.
It's because I'm worried.
What?
Professor Seo said
I should help with what I'm good at,
not with what I'm bad at.
So I analyzed your chart.
Your blood pressure baseline has been
slowly rising since two days ago.
Your blood pressure
was 150 over 90 this morning,
and you had a headache.
In my judgment,
I think you might be
developing pre-eclampsia.
What?
It can lead to seizures or convulsions.
I mean…
If you're that worried,
do it in the morning.
You can check then.
You see, your blood test results
will be available soon.
I was going to leave
after just seeing them.
I usually don't need much sleep,
and I just found out I snore.
Enough with the overreacting.
Doctor, over here!
Nurse, Ms. Cheon has collapsed!
Hurry! Please hook her up
to a monitor now!
Excuse me! Coming through!
Dr. Ku, this is for you.
Hey, you're back.
The fellow from Songdo Yulje
asked me to give this to you.
She said it was important
and to deliver it quickly.
She asked you to call her
once you receive it.
Okay.
Right. I almost forgot about this.
-Thanks.
-Don't mention it.
Goodbye.
Dr. Oh, watch the surgery?
You haven't seen a twin delivery yet.
Well…
That's okay.
I'll get going.
All right, then. Bye.
-Is everything ready?
-Yes.
-Please bring the patient.
-Okay.
Dr. Oh.
Hello.
Did you know Dr. Joo got an earful
from our professor because of you?
Sorry?
What does "general" mean?
I'm asking what "general" means.
General anesthesia--
"General" includes
both general and spinal anesthesia.
You know there are two, right?
But if you just say "general,"
how are we supposed to know
if it's general or spinal?
You need to communicate
properly and precisely.
These are basic fundamentals.
Until now, we've always used
"spinal" for spinal anesthesia.
Only general anesthesia
was called "general."
So I did exactly that.
So it's our mistake?
Then repeat exactly what you said
at that time.
Say it again.
Let's get to the bottom of this.
Doctor, at the time, I--
Wait. Do you not remember what you said?
Say it again. Let me hear it.
Go ahead.
Say it.
Repeat exactly what you said at that time.
"Ms. Jang Mi-hwa."
"Her baby's heart rate isn't good,
so please use general."
That's exactly the same
as what I said today.
I don't understand
what the problem is, Doctor.
What?
Then… why was the preparation wrong?
If you're uncomfortable
with our current way of communication,
you should discuss that
with our department's professors.
We've all used this terminology,
so it's not something
we can resolve at our level.
Well…
I didn't mean we should change it.
It's just that things go wrong
whenever she's involved.
I was just double-checking.
Especially after last time.
Last time? What are you referring to?
Sang-hyeon told me
that to get an OR
for a C-section at night,
Dr. Oh lied and said it was an emergency.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Dr. Kim, about that--
That's not true.
That might've been the outcome,
but Dr. Oh wouldn't have lied
to secure an OR.
Our first-years don't work that way.
I never taught them that,
and that's never happened before.
Dr. Myeong here would know too.
What?
Right. Actually,
I was going to mention this.
I guess there was
a bit of a mix-up that day.
Sorry.
Well, it seems like we're all ready.
I should go scrub in now.
Did something happen?
Well…
Dr. Um told me this.
When he was with Dr. Oh,
Dr. Myeong called
and said it was an emergency.
That's why Dr. Oh made the urgent request.
Yes, I heard that too.
Really?
In that case,
you should've told me.
I apologize.
I really didn't lie.
I'm not that kind of person.
But it's true that we did cause trouble
for Anesthesiology.
I'd like to apologize for that.
We'll make sure
such misunderstandings won't happen again.
And,
from now on,
I'll discipline our first-years myself.
If they do something wrong,
please tell me directly.
I'll scold them myself.
All right, then.
Let's hurry up and get ready.
Are you going to stay?
Yes.
RECOVERY ROOM
Doctor.
Is my baby okay? Is everything all right?
Yes.
Can I go see my baby?
I'm feeling okay.
No, you can't.
I mean…
You need to rest
for about six to eight hours.
And you'll feel too dizzy to walk anyway.
I mean…
It'll be difficult for you to walk.
You
never change, do you?
No.
So…
You said I shouldn't be a doctor,
so I thought about quitting.
But I really want to be one.
It's the only thing I want to do.
Then do it.
I only said that out of anger.
I'm not someone
who wants to stand in your way.
I was originally
supposed to have twins.
But then I ended up
with only one baby at 30 weeks.
Yes, I read your chart.
Clothes, pacifiers, strollers…
I bought two of everything.
But now I have one extra of everything.
I'm sure no one would want them
since they belonged to a baby who died.
But I can't bring myself
to throw them away either.
So…
I'm planning to have another child.
I see.
Geez. Just the thought
of doing IVF again makes me sick.
But I'm going to do it again.
So, Doctor,
will you deliver my second baby?
Since it'll be another C-section,
I'd be extracting the baby,
not delivering it.
And if you get pregnant too soon,
the risk of premature birth increases--
Gosh, I'm apologizing!
I'm saying I'm sorry, Doctor!
I see.
I'd like to apologize as well.
And thank you…
for saying that.
JONGNO YULJE MEDICAL CENTER
They don't even know I ran away.
So what am I doing here?
PYO NAM-KYUNG
Hey!
Geez, you startled me.
What?
What are you doing? Why aren't you here?
Hurry up.
Don't you know we need you?
What do you mean,
you need me?
What is it? Did you miss me? A lot?
Whatever. Just get over here this instant.
I received your document, Doctor.
Thank you
for bringing our first-year back.
But how did you know?
I'd never seen a first-year
with a backpack that big
when transferring a patient.
Be good to her, Do-won. Okay?
Okay, I will.
By the way…
I only saw her briefly,
but she seemed pretty decent.
She reminded me of you as a first-year.
Come on, I was like that?
No way. I was good at my job.
Have a good one. I'm hanging up.
Okay, bye. Thank you.
You scared me.
Good work today.
Thanks. You too.
What is it?
Hurry and go home.
Okay.
Are you sick or something?
No.
Then go home.
Okay.
You're coming tomorrow, right?
You better not run away.
Yes. I'll be here tomorrow.
Not just tomorrow but every single day.
You need to keep at it.
You're not going anywhere.
Don't forget.
Yi-young, you're 50 million in debt.
Don't forget that.
I better see you tomorrow, Yi-young.
Bye.
What took you so long? Hurry and sit.
What? Is something up?
There's always something going on.
Hey, did you miss me a lot?
Were you waiting a long time?
Yeah, we totally missed you.
Really? Why?
Don't you know?
We can't go home without you.
She told us not to call
if all of us weren't present.
She's so cruel.
For the group report?
In any case,
it's true that you need me. Right?
-Of course.
-That goes without saying.
MYEONG EUN-WON
I'll go first.
Hello, Dr. Myeong.
I have nothing to report today.
I didn't tend to any patients.
-Sorry?
-What? Do we have to start over?
How? He has nothing to report.
Maybe she doesn't understand.
I see. Thank you.
She said we don't have to do
group reports anymore.
What?
Senior residents
will report everything themselves!
-Really?
-Yeah.
Does that mean…
We can go home!
What are you guys doing?
Hurry up and get changed!
Hurry up. Let's go.
It's hot. Why is it so hot?
Because it's a hot Americano.
By the way,
how did you convince Dr. Myeong
to stop taking reports?
She's notorious for being unreasonable.
It's the price for me
turning a blind eye to what she did.
-What?
-You don't have to know.
Does this mean I can start
assigning work to Jae-il tomorrow?
I can't keep doing his work any longer.
Okay, you're all clear starting from now.
They'll stick around for a while.
It's all thanks
to my food shuttle service.
A full stomach makes you happy
and keeps you from wanting to quit.
No, Doctor. It's all about sleep.
A good sleep resets your mood.
To put Dr. Um to sleep,
I assisted in surgeries
and wrote up charts.
And I didn't want him
feeling hurt in the ward,
so I tried really hard to keep him away.
It's neither food nor sleep.
Is this your first day?
You don't know anything.
Gosh, it's hot!
Are you stupid?
It's today.
Today is the day.
What day?
It's payday.
That's right. No wonder.
-I was in a particularly good mood today.
-Right.
Speaking of which,
let's go out for dinner.
It's my treat.
I do earn a bit more than you.
-Really?
-Okay? Let's go.
Yes! Let's get something expensive!
I know a place.
I got my paycheck!
Hey, did you get yours too?
-Yeah.
And I'm still in the red. What a drag.
Isn't it tradition to buy our parents
long johns with our first paycheck?
Sa-bi, what are you going to do?
Who buys long johns these days?
Thermal clothing is the trend.
I'm going to put all this money
into booking a summer vacation.
We get vacations?
Of course. What kind of job
doesn't have vacations?
I'm hungry.
I haven't eaten all day.
Hey, should we have dinner together
to celebrate our first paycheck?
The pasta place across the street
is probably open until late.
Isn't pasta a bit heavy at night?
I don't eat much at night.
I eat alone in the evening.
It's what I prefer.
I'll get going first.
Okay.
-See you tomorrow.
-Bye.
Next time.
We can eat together next time.
-Hello?
-Dr. Um.
We're at a pasta place across the street.
If you haven't eaten--
I'll be there right now.
Thank you, Doctor.
THANKS TO OUR SPECIAL GUEST, AHN EUN-JIN,
OUR ETERNAL CHU MIN-HA
RESIDENT PLAYBOOK
First-years have a lot to do.
They're still a bit slow,
so it takes longer to do things.
You see, I'm still a first-year resident.
I can't tell you
anything definitive right now.
You all kept saying you didn't know, so…
How do you know
even less than your patient?
Is that so difficult?
These are the basics!
Whenever things get a little hard,
you show it.
You can't even get that right?
How can we not show
we're struggling when it's hard?
Forcing yourself to work is hard.
You little brat!
What's the point of just filling your head
with reading and studying?
The real world isn't just about studying.
Look at you, Um Jay!
Me? Is that for me?
Wouldn't he be the first
among OB-GYN first-years?
If you're not sure, just say this.
What's so simple about this solution?
You don't know either.
Isn't this profound?
Where's Ku Do-won?
I don't see the chief resident.
He kept looking and smiling.
What else could it be?
It's love.
Subtitle translation by: Sooji Kim